<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Azure AD B2C on The Bearded Code Monkey</title><link>https://blog.hgaard.com/tags/azure-ad-b2c/</link><description>Recent content in Azure AD B2C on The Bearded Code Monkey</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.hgaard.com/tags/azure-ad-b2c/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Managing external users with Azure AD B2C</title><link>https://blog.hgaard.com/managing-external-users-with-azure-ad-b2c/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.hgaard.com/managing-external-users-with-azure-ad-b2c/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The last few weeks I have been working with a customer to implement Azure AD B2C login for their internal systems and I thought I might share my experience with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="what-is-azure-ad-b2c"&gt;What is Azure AD B2C&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First of all I might need to explain a few things, like what B2C is (assuming here that you know what Azure and AD are) and what kind of problem I am solving with it. First of all the name B2C simply means business to consumer and is in preview with another new variant of AD called B2B (Business to Business). It is intended to make it easier to set up authentication with multiple social identity providers like Facebook, Google or LinkedIn as easy as can be. But B2C also provides a way to sign up users without a social identity by providing a local account type - which in turn really is just a modified version of an AD account. For the local account B2C provides all the necessary plumbing like signup, password and user management, such that the consuming application never need to store any sensitive information. You can find a lot more information in the B2C documentation &lt;a href="https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/documentation/services/active-directory-b2c/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>