<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Getting Started on The Bearded Code Monkey</title><link>https://blog.hgaard.com/tags/getting-started/</link><description>Recent content in Getting Started on The Bearded Code Monkey</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.hgaard.com/tags/getting-started/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Doing stuff with RethinkDB</title><link>https://blog.hgaard.com/doinng-stuff-with-rethinkdb/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.hgaard.com/doinng-stuff-with-rethinkdb/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I recently started a new job. Actually I moved from Copenhagen to Brisbane, Australia with my whole family, just to try living and working in a different country - and of course to give our 3 kids and ourselves a great experience/ adventure. Anyway, I got a job in the Australian consultancy &lt;a href="http://readify.net" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Readify&lt;/a&gt; and one of the perks there is PD or Professional Development for up to 20 days a year. 20 days where I can work with/learn whatever I feel like (well almost. I need to justify the relevance of the topic and I have to produce something that my colleagues can benefit from too). Yeah I know pretty sweet! So the last 2 days I have had my first PD and my goal was to get familiar with &lt;a href="https://www.rethinkdb.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;RethinkDB&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Setting up this blog</title><link>https://blog.hgaard.com/setting-up-this-blog/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2015 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.hgaard.com/setting-up-this-blog/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction &lt;a href="#introduction" class="anchor"&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have had this blog brewing for a while, but have not really had the time to finish it before - I might get back to why in a later post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway here goes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started out hosting it on Heroku. It&amp;rsquo;s a great way of hosting web applications and you can start out on their free tier which also has a lot of free add-ons like Postgres and New Relic. How ever i like to tinker and a Pluralsight course - &lt;a href="https://app.pluralsight.com/library/courses/master-domain/table-of-contents" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Mastering Your Own Domain&lt;/a&gt; by Rob Conery - inspired me to be more in control. For instructions on how to run Ghost on Heroku I used &lt;a href="http://www.therightcode.net/deploy-ghost-to-heroku-for-free/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; guide by &lt;a href="http://www.therightcode.net/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Greg Bergé&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>