<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>The Bearded Code Monkey</title><link>https://blog.hgaard.com/</link><description>Recent content on The Bearded Code Monkey</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.hgaard.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>3 awesome podcast episodes</title><link>https://blog.hgaard.com/3-awesome-podcasts/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.hgaard.com/3-awesome-podcasts/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I recently went through my draft posts and found this little post about 3 podcasts, I at the time thought were quite awesome. For some reason, I never got around to publishing it, but since I still think they are quite awesome here they are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I thought I might share a few good podcasts I&amp;rsquo;ve listened to recently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://changelog.com/podcast/189" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Yehuda Katz - Rails/Ember/Rust&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://changelog.com/podcast/194" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Jose Valim - Elixir &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://changelog.com/podcast/202" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Matz (Yukihiro Matsumoto) - Ruby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main reason I found these podcast interesting is that it tells the story behind some very prominent people in our industry and for 2 of them, it seems they started in programming by pure accident and turned out awesome!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Avoid The Microservice Fallacy</title><link>https://blog.hgaard.com/avoid-the-microservice-fallacy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.hgaard.com/avoid-the-microservice-fallacy/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Last year I had the pleasure of speaking at the DDD conference here in &lt;a href="http://dddbrisbane.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Brisbane&lt;/a&gt;. It was a really good experience and I enjoyed doing the talk a lot. One of the great things about the DDD conference is the engagement of the audience and community and thus the amount of feedback you get as a speaker. A lot of the comments I got were really positive which I obviously appreciate immensely. But I also got quite a lot of good suggestions on things to improve, like;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>You should use git even though you can't</title><link>https://blog.hgaard.com/you-should-use-git-even-thoug-you-cant/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.hgaard.com/you-should-use-git-even-thoug-you-cant/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="why"&gt;Why &lt;a href="#why" class="anchor"&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;As a consultant, I sometimes work with clients that aren&amp;rsquo;t using the best source control software that is currently available. This sometimes means that git is not the preferred tool for source control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though you can&amp;rsquo;t always control the infrastructure of your workplace, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t need to be an excuse to stick with suboptimal tools to do your job. You are better than that!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My main gripe with TFS (or any centralized source control system that I know of) is the branching story. The lack of easy &lt;em&gt;local&lt;/em&gt; branching (and later, sharing of these) really inhibits my typical workflow. The fact that a centrally-controlled server is the only possible way to create such a branch is a fundamental problem with TFS and it&amp;rsquo;s tooling ecosystem, and cannot currently be solved without changing away from TFS. As a consequence, organisations that use TFS tend to treat the entire concept of a branch something that needs to be centrally controlled and managed.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Doing stuff with RethinkDB</title><link>https://blog.hgaard.com/doinng-stuff-with-rethinkdb/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.hgaard.com/doinng-stuff-with-rethinkdb/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I recently started a new job. Actually I moved from Copenhagen to Brisbane, Australia with my whole family, just to try living and working in a different country - and of course to give our 3 kids and ourselves a great experience/ adventure. Anyway, I got a job in the Australian consultancy &lt;a href="http://readify.net" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Readify&lt;/a&gt; and one of the perks there is PD or Professional Development for up to 20 days a year. 20 days where I can work with/learn whatever I feel like (well almost. I need to justify the relevance of the topic and I have to produce something that my colleagues can benefit from too). Yeah I know pretty sweet! So the last 2 days I have had my first PD and my goal was to get familiar with &lt;a href="https://www.rethinkdb.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;RethinkDB&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Managing external users with Azure AD B2C</title><link>https://blog.hgaard.com/managing-external-users-with-azure-ad-b2c/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.hgaard.com/managing-external-users-with-azure-ad-b2c/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The last few weeks I have been working with a customer to implement Azure AD B2C login for their internal systems and I thought I might share my experience with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="what-is-azure-ad-b2c"&gt;What is Azure AD B2C &lt;a href="#what-is-azure-ad-b2c" class="anchor"&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;First of all I might need to explain a few things, like what B2C is (assuming here that you know what Azure and AD are) and what kind of problem I am solving with it. First of all the name B2C simply means business to consumer and is in preview with another new variant of AD called B2B (Business to Business). It is intended to make it easier to set up authentication with multiple social identity providers like Facebook, Google or LinkedIn as easy as can be. But B2C also provides a way to sign up users without a social identity by providing a local account type - which in turn really is just a modified version of an AD account. For the local account B2C provides all the necessary plumbing like signup, password and user management, such that the consuming application never need to store any sensitive information. You can find a lot more information in the B2C documentation &lt;a href="https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/documentation/services/active-directory-b2c/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Setting up this blog</title><link>https://blog.hgaard.com/setting-up-this-blog/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2015 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.hgaard.com/setting-up-this-blog/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction &lt;a href="#introduction" class="anchor"&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have had this blog brewing for a while, but have not really had the time to finish it before - I might get back to why in a later post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway here goes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started out hosting it on Heroku. It&amp;rsquo;s a great way of hosting web applications and you can start out on their free tier which also has a lot of free add-ons like Postgres and New Relic. How ever i like to tinker and a Pluralsight course - &lt;a href="https://app.pluralsight.com/library/courses/master-domain/table-of-contents" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Mastering Your Own Domain&lt;/a&gt; by Rob Conery - inspired me to be more in control. For instructions on how to run Ghost on Heroku I used &lt;a href="http://www.therightcode.net/deploy-ghost-to-heroku-for-free/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; guide by &lt;a href="http://www.therightcode.net/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Greg Bergé&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Getting started with git in Visual Studio</title><link>https://blog.hgaard.com/getting-started-with-git-in-visual-studio/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.hgaard.com/getting-started-with-git-in-visual-studio/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The last year or so at &lt;a href="http://schultz.dk" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Schultz&lt;/a&gt; we have started to use git for more and more projects, and I have become the goto guy for git related issues. The last few times new developers have joined my project or started a new project using I have compiled an email with useful links on git and git from Visual Studio. So thought I might just put it in a blog post instead.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Installing Windows 8.1 on my mac</title><link>https://blog.hgaard.com/setting-up-my-new-mac/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.hgaard.com/setting-up-my-new-mac/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I recently got a new machine. And since i do a fair bit of iOS development (through Xamarin) I chose to get a mac. However, since I still do most of my work on Windows I would like to be able to boot it directly into Windows. No problem I thought, mac has Bootcamp. I&amp;rsquo;ll just install the newest version of Windows using the Bootcamp assistant. Well everything went well until the Windows installation had to update the boot record. I popped a message box stating that &amp;ldquo;Could not update the boot configuration&amp;rdquo;. No way to continue!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Finding big files in a git repo on windows</title><link>https://blog.hgaard.com/finding-big-files-in-a-git-repo-on-windows/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.hgaard.com/finding-big-files-in-a-git-repo-on-windows/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I recently joined a project that had been working on a product for a few years already. The team had used TFS for source control until just a few weeks before I joined. Because of external circumstances the team had decided to migrate the complete source tree to git (still hosted on TFS though).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the migration to the new git repository it turned out that the repository was quite big, to more precise it was around 1,2 GB. This could of course just be ignored since TFS repositories with a few years of age can easily grow to that size - we stick anything in there don&amp;rsquo;t we. Anyway with a recent &lt;a href="http://thedailywtf.com/articles/Forever-Alone" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;story in mind&lt;/a&gt; and because we had to do a lot of cloning of the repository, I decided to have a closer look at the repo to see if we had any big files checked in by mistake.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Setting up a difftool for git on windows</title><link>https://blog.hgaard.com/setting-up-a-difftool-for-git-on-windows/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.hgaard.com/setting-up-a-difftool-for-git-on-windows/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Well i have been using &lt;a href="https://sourcegear.com/diffmerge/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;DiffMerge&lt;/a&gt; from SourceGear as the default diff tool in Visual Studio for quite a few years now. I use git more and more now but I never took the time to add a diff tool to the git configuration. But since i recently got a new dev machine I thought i might just set that up as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="installation"&gt;Installation &lt;a href="#installation" class="anchor"&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I installed with &lt;a href="http://chocolatey.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Chocolatey&lt;/a&gt; (remember to run cmd og PowerShell as admin) which i use to manage most of my dev tools. In fact i maintain a script on github with all the tools I use, so if you haven&amp;rsquo;t used Chocolatey for application installation, now&amp;rsquo;s your chance.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://blog.hgaard.com/about/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.hgaard.com/about/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I am a Danish full stack software engineer and architect with
15y+ experience. I do web, security cross-platform mobile development
and everything in-between. I am known to be a person who challenges
the well-known with a positive mind, both when it comes to building
solutions, improving the development process and choosing platform,
language or technology. I am inspired by functional programming languages,
which is reflected in my approach to programming and I strive
to become a polyglot developer. Privately I am a father of two boys and a
girl and married to a sociologist doing UX Research. We live in Brisbane,
but are often found hanging out on the local beaches trying to surf and
play with our kids.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Hello blog</title><link>https://blog.hgaard.com/hello-blog/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.hgaard.com/hello-blog/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This is an introduction post!
Oh well I guess one can&amp;rsquo;t stat a blog without some kind of introduction.
I&amp;rsquo;m software developer, a husband, a dad and a lot of other stuff. I really enjoy working in technology and I truly get thrilled when diving into new shiny languages, frameworks and tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m starting this blog because I want to archive some my thoughts and programming experiments. Who know it might be useful later.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>